Guide to the Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 7. Campaign Files, 1976-2004 TJU.2010.01.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 7. Campaign Files
1976-2004
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Specter, Arlen
TJU.2010.01.07
31.25 Linear Feet
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 7. Campaign Files documents eight major campaigns in Specter's political career. Specter served as U.S. Senator from 1981 to 2011, making him the longest-tenured Pennsylvanian senator. This group contains camapign flyers, reports, correspondence, polling data, newsclips, opposition research, and memos.
Custodial History
Material was transferred to the care of Philadelphia University in 2010-2011 from the Federal Records Storage Facility in Suitland, Maryland, as well as the Senator's Washington, D.C. and Pennsylvania offices. The physical material was transferred to the University of Pittsburgh in 2014, with the exception of selected photographic and memorabilia items that remain at the Arlen Specter Center's Roxboro House for display. In 2016, Philadelphia University merged with Thomas Jefferson University, and is now known as Thomas Jefferson University- East Falls campus.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Arlen Specter to Philadelphia University in 2010. Philadelphia University and the University of Pittsburgh entered into a partnership to jointly manage the collection in 2013.
Biography
Born in Wichita, Kansas, on February 12, 1930, Arlen Specter came to Pennsylvania to attend the University of Pennsylvania. He married Joan Levy in 1953, and graduated from Yale Law School in 1956. He became assistant district attorney in Philadelphia in 1959. In 1962, Specter was recommended to serve on the Warren Commission, assembled to investigate the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. As part of the Commission, he was responsible for co-authoring the proposal of the "single bullet theory," determining that one bullet struck both President Kennedy and Texas Governor John Connally. Specter ran for Philadelphia district attorney in 1965, switching his Party membership to Republican in order to unseat the incumbent Democrat. He was successful, and served as district attorney from 1966 to 1974.
After an initial failed run for Senator and then for Governor of Pennsylvania, Specter was elected to the U.S. Senate in 1980. He would stay in this position from 1981 to 2011, making him the longest-tenured senator in Pennsylvania's history. During this time, he was a member of a number of Committees: Judiciary (1981-2011; Chair, 2007-2007), Appropriations (1981-2011), Veterans Affairs (1981-2011; Chair, 1997-2001 and 2003-2005), Select Intelligence (1985-1991; 1995-1997; Chair, 1995-1997), Special Aging (1991-1995; 2007-2011), Governmental Affairs (1997-2001; 2003-2005), and Environment and Public Works (2001-2003; 2009-2011).
Though elected as a Republican, Specter was a moderate on many issues, including healthcare reform, immigration, and abortion. He would often cross party lines, such as in voting against the confirmation of President Ronald Reagan's nominee Judge Robert Bork to the Supreme Court in 1987. Specter would again come into the spotlight during a Supreme Court nomination process in 1991, for his cross-examination of Professor Anita Hill regarding her allegations against nominee Clarence Thomas. In 1999, he would vote against the charges brought against President Bill Clinton, giving an answer of "not proven" to reflect his belief that Clinton had not received a fair trial.
As Senator, Specter championed a number of causes and influenced many legislative areas. He was frequently a member of Congressional Delegation trips, particularly to the Middle East, where he would speak out on the cause of freedom from religious persecution and the importance of strong diplomatic relations. He was also a proponent of funding for medical research, including the use of stem cells. He advocated for strict crime laws, particularly for career criminals. His focus on benefitting Pennsylvania could be seen through the pursuit of grant funding opportunities and his attempt to prevent the closure of the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard in the 1990s.
With the worsening of Congressional partisanship in the late 2000s, Specter found himself frequently voting with his Democratic peers. After being one of only three handful of Republicans to vote for the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act in 2009, Specter found himself increasingly marginalized within his party. In April 2009, he returned to the Democratic Party, helping to ensure the passage of the Affordable Care Act. Seeking re-election in 2010, he was defeated in the Democratic primary by Joe Sestak.
Specter's 30-year tenure in the Senate concluded in January 2011. After leaving the Senate, he partnered with Philadelphia University (now Jefferson-East Falls) to establish the Arlen Specter Center for Public Service. In the fall of 2012, Specter, who had previously beaten Hodgkin's lymphoma in 2005 while serving as Chair of the Judiciary Committee, was diagnosed with cancer. He died on October 14, 2012, aged 82.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
Group 7 is arranged into eight series detailing information about Specter's campaigns for political office:
Series I. 1976 Senatorial Campaign, 1976
Series II. 1978 Gubernatorial Campaign, 1978
Series III. 1980 Senatorial Campaign, 1980
Series IV. 1986 Senatorial Campaign, 1984-1986
Series V. 1992 Senatorial Campaign, 1991-1992
Series VI. 1996 Presidential Campaign, 1985-1996
Series VII. 1998 Senatorial Campaign, 1980-1998
Series VIII. 2004 Senatorial Campaign, 1980-2004
Scope and Content Notes
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 7. Campaign Files comprises 25 boxes of material documenting eight major campaigns in Specter's political career. This includes documentation of all of his successful Senate runs (1980, 1986, 1992, 1998, and 2004), as well as his failed campaigns for Senate in 1976, Governor of Pennsylvania in 1978, and President in 1996. The group contains camapign flyers, reports, correspondence, polling data, newsclips, opposition research, and memos.
Related Material
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 1. Pre-Senatorial Career Files, 1953-1980, TJU.2010.01.01
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 2. Legislative Files, 1965-2011, TJU.2010.01.02
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 3. Personal, Political and Official Files, 1944-2010, TJU.2010.01.03
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 4. Office Administration Files, 1962-2010, TJU.2010.01.04
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 5. Constituent Services Files, 1976-2007, TJU.2010.01.05
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files, 1972-2010, TJU.2010.01.06
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 8. Awards and Memorabilia, 1957-2010, TJU.2010.01.08
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 9. Photographs, 1930-2010, TJU.2010.01.09
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 10. Electronic Records, 1980-2010, TJU.2010.01.10
Political campaigns -- Pennsylvania; Pennsylvania; Elections -- Pennsylvania; Politicians; Pennsylvania. Governor; Republican Party (Pa.); United States. Congress. Senate; Stephen Freind; Toomey, Pat; Yeakel, Lynn; Edgar, Bob; Thornburgh, Dick; Heinz, John; Specter, Arlen
- 1976 Senatorial Campaign, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  1976 Senatorial Campaign materials include information on Specter's campaign against John Heinz for the Republican nomination for US Senator. He was defeated in the primary.
  - General campaign files, 1976 (Box 1238)
- 1978 Gubernatorial Campaign, II.
  1978 Gubernatorial Campaign materials include information on Specter's campaign against Dick Thornburgh for the Republican nomination for Governor of Pennsylvania. He was defeated in the primary.
  - General campaign files, 1978 (Box 1239)
- 1980 Senatorial Campaign, III.
  1980 Senatorial Campaign materials include information on Specter's campaign against Democrat Pete Flaherty for the nomination for US Senator. He was successfully elected in November 1980.
  - Coal contacts, 1980 (Box 1240, Folder 1)
  - Debate transcripts, 1980 (Box 1240, Folder 2-3)
  - Endorsements, 1980 (Box 1240, Folder 4)
  - Labor, 1980 (Box 1240, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous campaign materials, 1980 (Box 1240, Folder 6)
  - Press clippings, 1980 (Box 1240, Folder 7)
  - Primary maps, 1980 (Box 1240, Folder 8)
  - Republican platform, 1980 (Box 1240, Folder 9)
  - Specter budgetary identification, 1980 (Box 1240, Folder 10)
- 1986 Senatorial Campaign, 1984-1986; IV.
  1986 Senatorial Campaign materials include information on Specter's campaign for US Senator. He ran against Richard Stokes for the Republican nomination in the primary, and against Democrat Bob Edgar in the general election. He was successfully re-elected in November 1986.
  - Primary, 1986; 1.
    - Democratic primary candidates, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 11)
    - Republican primary, Dick Thornburgh possible bid, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 12-13)
  - General Election, 1985-1985; 2.
    - Debates, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 14)
    - Bob Edgar, Campaign, Attacks on Specter, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 15)
    - Bob Edgar, Campaign, Financial statements, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 16-17)
    - Bob Edgar, Campaign, Mailings and press, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 18-19)
    - Bob Edgar, Co-sponsored measures, 95th Congress, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 20)
    - Bob Edgar, Co-sponsored measures, 96th Congress, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 21)
    - Bob Edgar, Co-sponsored measures, 97th Congress, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 22)
    - Bob Edgar, Co-sponsored measures, 98th Congress, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 23)
    - Bob Edgar, Co-sponsored measures, 98th Congress, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 24)
    - Bob Edgar, Federal Election Commission (FEC) complaint, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 25)
    - Bob Edgar, Position papers, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 26)
    - Bob Edgar, Presidential support and party loyalty, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 27)
    - Bob Edgar, Sponsored measures, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 28)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, 1985 (Box 1240, Folder 29)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 30)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Appropriations, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 31)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Budget, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 32)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Crime, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 33)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Defense, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 34)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Economy, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 35)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Energy and water projects, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 36)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Environment, 1986 (Box 1240, Folder 37)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Foreign policy, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 1)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Government, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 2)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Jobs and labor, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 3)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Military construction, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 4)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Miscellaneous, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 5)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Missed votes, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 6)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Social issues, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 7)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Social Security, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 8)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Taxes, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 9)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Trade, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 10)
    - Bob Edgar, Voting records, Transportation, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 11)
    - Bob Edgar, Vulnerability study, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 12-14)
    - Fundraising, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 15-16)
    - Pennsylvania research, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 17)
    - Post-election performance evaluations, 1986 (Box 1241, Folder 18)
    - Press, 1984-March 1985 (Box 1241, Folder 19)
    - Press, March-April 1985 (Box 1241, Folder 20)
    - Press, April-May 1985 (Box 1242, Folder 1)
    - Press, June-July 1985 (Box 1242, Folder 2)
    - Press, August 1985 (Box 1242, Folder 3)
    - Press, September 1985 (Box 1242, Folder 4)
    - Press, October-November 1985 (Box 1242, Folder 5)
    - Press, December 1985-January 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 6)
    - Press, February 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 7)
    - Press, March 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 8)
    - Press, April 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 9)
    - Press, May 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 10-11)
    - Press, June 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 12)
    - Press, July-August 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 13)
    - Press, September 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 14)
    - Press, October 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 15-17)
    - Press, November 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 18)
    - Questionnaires, 1986 (Box 1242, Folder 19-21)
    - Arlen Specter, Advertising and press, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 1)
    - Arlen Specter, Campaign brochures, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 2)
    - Arlen Specter, Campaign correspondence, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 3)
    - Arlen Specter, County accomplishments, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 4)
    - Arlen Specter, Endorsements, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 5)
    - Arlen Specter, Legislative achievements, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 6)
    - Arlen Specter, Legislative records, Children's issues, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 7)
    - Arlen Specter, Legislative records, Crime, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 8)
    - Arlen Specter, Legislative records, Israel and Jewish issues, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 9)
    - Arlen Specter, Pennsylvania accomplishments, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 10)
    - Arlen Specter, Pennsylvania newsletters, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 11)
    - Arlen Specter, Position papers, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 12)
    - Arlen Specter, Presidential support and opposition, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 13)
    - Arlen Specter, Voting records, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 14)
    - General campaign files, 1986 (Box 1243, Folder 15-35)
    - General campaign files, 1986 (Box 1244, Folder 1-10)
- 1992 Senatorial Campaign, 1991-1992; V.
  1992 Senatorial Campaign materials include information on Specter's campaign for US Senator. He ran against Stephen Freind for the Republican nomination in the primary, and against Democrat Lynn Yeakel in the general election. He was successfully re-elected in November 1992.
  - Primary, 1991-1992; 1.
    - Democratic primary, Debates, 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 11)
    - Democratic primary, Press, 1991-February 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 12)
    - Democratic Party, Press, April 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 13-14)
    - Primary voting guides and endorsements, 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 15)
    - Primary results, 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 16)
    - Republican primary, Campaign research and strategy, 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 17-18)
    - Republican primary, Debate, 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 19)
    - Republican primary, Steve Freind finanical filing, 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 20)
    - Republican primary, Steve Freind press, 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 21-22)
    - Republican primary, Opposition research, 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 23-24)
    - Republican primary, Press, 1991 (Box 1244, Folder 25)
    - Republican primary, Press, January 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 26)
    - Republican primary, Press, February 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 27)
    - Republican primary, Press, March 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 28)
    - Republican primary, Press, April 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 29)
  - General Election, 1992; 2.
    - Citizen's Jury, Philadelphia, 1992 (Box 1244, Folder 30-31)
    - Citizen's Jury, Pittsburgh, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 1-3)
    - Citizen's Jury, Television advertisements, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 4)
    - Debates, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 5)
    - FEC complaint, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 6)
    - Israel and Bryn Mawr Presbyterian, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 7)
    - Press, May 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 8)
    - Press, June-October 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 9)
    - Press, Campaign editorials, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 10)
    - Republican platform, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 11)
    - Arlen Specter, Brochures and newspaper ads, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 12)
    - Arlen Specter, Budget information, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 13)
    - Arlen Specter, Campaign conference and party information, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 14)
    - Arlen Specter, Complaint letters, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 15)
    - Arlen Specter, County activity reports, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 16)
    - Arlen Specter, Endorsements, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 17)
    - Arlen Specter, Legislative record and platform, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 18)
    - Arlen Specter, Media packet, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 19)
    - Arlen Specter, Press releases, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 20)
    - Arlen Specter, Television and radio ads, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 21-22)
    - Arlen Specter, Washington fundraiser, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 23)
    - Lynn Yeakel, Campaign gaffes, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 24)
    - Lynn Yeakel, Endorsements, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 25)
    - Lynn Yeakel, Fundraising, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 26)
    - Lynn Yeakel, Interviews and speeches, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 27)
    - Lynn Yeakel, Vulnerability study, 1992 (Box 1245, Folder 28)
    - General campaign files, 1992 (Box 1246)
    - General campaign files, 1992 (Box 1247)
    - General campaign files, 1992 (Box 1248)
    - General campaign files, 1992 (Box 1249)
- 1996 Presidential Campaign, 1985-1996; VI.
  1996 Presidential Campaign materials include information on Specter's campaign for the Republican nomination for President. He was one among a number of contenders, including eventual nominee Bob Dole. Specter suspended his campaign in November 1995 to support Dole.
  - Analysis of campaign financial requirements, 1996 (Box 1250, Folder 1)
  - Big Tent Political Action Committee (PAC), 1996 (Box 1250, Folder 2-3)
  - Campaign issues, Abortion, 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 4)
  - Campaign issues, Flat tax plan, 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 5)
  - Campaign trips, 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 6)
  - Campaign trips, Arizona, 1994-1995 (Box 1250, Folder 7)
  - Campaign trips, California, 1994-1995 (Box 1250, Folder 8)
  - Campaign trips, Iowa, 1994-1995 (Box 1250, Folder 9)
  - Campaign trips, Maine, 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 10)
  - Campaign trips, Minnesota, 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 11)
  - Campaign trips, New Hampshire, 1994-1995 (Box 1250, Folder 12-13)
  - Campaign trips, Rhode Island, 1993-1995 (Box 1250, Folder 14)
  - FEC regulations and complaints, 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 15)
  - Internet campaigns, 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 16)
  - Labor contracts, 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous campaign notes, 1994-1995 (Box 1250, Folder 18)
  - Presidential candidate fundraising, 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 19)
  - Presidential primary dates, 1994-1996 (Box 1250, Folder 20)
  - Press, 1993 (Box 1250, Folder 21)
  - Press, April 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 22)
  - Press, May 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 23)
  - Press, June 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 24)
  - Press, July 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 25)
  - Press, August 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 26)
  - Press, September 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 27)
  - Press, October 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 28)
  - Press, November 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 29)
  - Press, December 1994 (Box 1250, Folder 30)
  - Press, January 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 31)
  - Press, February 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 32)
  - Press, March 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 33-34)
  - Press, April 1985 (Box 1250, Folder 35)
  - Press, May 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 36)
  - Press, June 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 37)
  - Press, July 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 38)
  - Press, August 1995 (Box 1250, Folder 39)
  - Press, September 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 1)
  - Press, October 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 2)
  - Press, November 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 3)
  - Press, December 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 4)
  - Press, January 1996 (Box 1251, Folder 5)
  - Press, February 1996 (Box 1251, Folder 6)
  - Press, 1996 (Box 1251, Folder 7)
  - Press, Specter profiles, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 8)
  - Public opinion polls, 1994-1995 (Box 1251, Folder 9)
  - Religious views, 1985-1995 (Box 1251, Folder 10)
  - Reports of receipts and disbursements, Appril 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 11)
  - Reports of receipts and disbursements, October 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 12)
  - Republican events and organization, 1994-1995 (Box 1251, Folder 13)
  - Republican primary candidates, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 14)
  - Republican primary candidates, Colin Powell, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 15)
  - Republican primary candidates, Pete Wilson, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 16)
  - Republican primary polls, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 17)
  - Arlen Specter, Articles, 1994-1995 (Box 1251, Folder 18)
  - Arlen Specter, Brochures and ads, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 19)
  - Arlen Specter, Campaign announcement, 1994-1995 (Box 1251, Folder 20)
  - Arlen Specter, Campaign fundraising memos, 1994-1995 (Box 1251, Folder 21)
  - Arlen Specter, Campaign memos, 1994-1995 (Box 1251, Folder 22-23)
  - Arlen Specter, Campaign press releases, 1994-1995 (Box 1251, Folder 24-25)
  - Arlen Specter, Campaign staff, 1994-1995 (Box 1251, Folder 26)
  - Arlen Specter, Campaign travel schedule, 1995-1996 (Box 1251, Folder 27)
  - Arlen Specter, Campaign websites, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 28)
  - Arlen Specter, End of campaign, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 29)
  - Arlen Specter, Endorsements, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 30)
  - Arlen Specter, Position papers, 1994 (Box 1251, Folder 31)
  - Arlen Specter, Speeches, 1994 (Box 1251, Folder 32)
  - Arlen Specter, Television and radio ads and appearances, 1995 (Box 1251, Folder 33)
  - General campaign files, 1996 (Box 1252)
- 1998 Senatorial Campaign, 1980-1998; VII.
  1998 Senatorial Campaign materials include information on Specter's campaign for US Senator. He ran against Larry Murphy and Tom Lingenfelter for the Republican nomination in the primary, and against Democrat Bill Lloyd in the general election. He was successfully re-elected in November 1998.
  - FEC audit, 1980-1997 (Box 1253, Folder 1-2)
  - Press, 1997 (Box 1253, Folder 3)
  - Press, January 1998 (Box 1253, Folder 4)
  - Press, February 1998 (Box 1253, Folder 5)
  - Press, March 1998 (Box 1253, Folder 6)
  - Press, April 1998 (Box 1253, Folder 7)
  - Press, May 1998 (Box 1253, Folder 8)
  - Press, June-July 1998 (Box 1253, Folder 9)
  - Press, August-September 1998 (Box 1253, Folder 10)
  - Press, October-November 1998 (Box 1253, Folder 11)
  - Arlen Specter, Campaign material, 1998 (Box 1253, Folder 12)
  - General campaign files, 1998 (Box 1254)
  - General campaign files, 1998 (Box 1255)
  - General campaign files, 1998 (Box 1256)
  - General campaign files, 1998 (Box 1257)
  - General campaign files, 1998 (Box 1258)
  - General campaign files, 1998 (Box 1259)
- 2004 Senatorial Campaign, 1980-2004; VIII.
  2004 Senatorial Campaign materials include information on Specter's campaign for US Senator. He ran against Pat Toomey for the Republican nomination in the primary, and against Democrat Joe Hoeffel in the general election. He was successfully re-elected in November 2004.
  - Primary, 1980-2003; 1.
    - Specter primary results, 1980-1998 (Box 1253, Folder 13)
    - Specter reflection on primary, 2003 (Box 1253, Folder 14)
    - Specter research on candidates, 2003 (Box 1253, Folder 15)
  - General Election, 1980-2004; 2.
    - American Conservative Union ratings, 2000-2002 (Box 1253, Folder 16)
    - Citizens against Government Waste, 2001-2003 (Box 1253, Folder 17)
    - Democratic senatorial campaign committee speculations, 2003 (Box 1253, Folder 18)
    - Letters by Specter, 2003 (Box 1253, Folder 19)
    - Letters to Specter, 2003 (Box 1253, Folder 20)
    - National Federation of Independent Businesses rating, 1994-2003 (Box 1253, Folder 21)
    - National Taxpayers Union, 1992-2002 (Box 1253, Folder 22)
    - Party unity, 2000-2002 (Box 1253, Folder 23)
    - Promotion for Specter, 2003 (Box 1253, Folder 24)
    - Presidential support for Specter, 1986-2004 (Box 1253, Folder 25)
    - Press, 2003 (Box 1253, Folder 26)
    - Previous fiscal year information, 1981-2004 (Box 1253, Folder 27)
    - Schedule, 2003-2004 (Box 1253, Folder 28)
    - Senate rules and ethics, 2003 (Box 1253, Folder 29)
    - Arlen Specter, Accomplishments, 1980-2004 (Box 1253, Folder 30)